Finding Aid for The Budd Company records
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The Budd Company records 1912-1951 1920-1923
Budd Company
1.25 linear feet and 3 outsized volumes
2013046 Aa 2
The Budd Company record group consists of materials from the early 1900s, which mainly pertains to the company's Detroit operations. The bulk of the records include company ledgers.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group was donated by Gary and Kathy Mulqueeney (donor no. 10913 ) in April 2013.
No further additions to the records are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Best known for the fabrication of stainless steel and automobile components, the Budd Company was originally founded in Philadelphia, Penn., in 1912, by Edward G. Budd, as Edward G. Budd Manufacturing Company. After some success the company merged with its subsidiary, the Budd Wheel Company, founded by Edward G. Budd in Philadelphia in 1916, and became a pioneer in the development of steel car bodies.
In 1925, the Budd Company purchased a manufacturing plant in Detroit, Michigan and also began to explore the European market. Further endeavors lead the company to develop innovations in, not only the automobile industry, but also the railroad, aviation, and plastics industries. In 1972, the Budd Company officially moved its headquarters to Troy, Michigan, and by the 1980s, the company focused solely on the automobile industry.
In 1978 the Budd Company was acquired by Thyssen AG and changed its name to ThyssenKrupp Budd. In 2006 the company was purchased by Martinrea International.
The records of The Budd Company are comprised of Administrative Files, which include a supervisor's manual, contracts, and general ledgers. A complete collection of The Budd Company records can be found at Hagley Museum in Wilmington, Delaware.
Subjects:
Budd Company.; Automobile industry and trade--United States.; Automobiles--Parts.; Manufacturing industries--Michigan--Detroit.
Genre Terms:
Ledgers (account books).
- Administrative Files
  - Budd Supervisor's Manual, 1946, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Contracts relating to the new Ambi-Budd set-up, 1930 (Box 1)
    (includes the Budd International Corporation By-Laws and Amended Certificate of Incorporation)
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc. Lease Agreement, 1951 (Box 1)
  - General Ledgers
    - Journal Vouchers, 1921-1922, 3 volumes (Box 2)
    - Krouse Fatigue Machine Co., 1938 (Box 2)
    - Krouse Testing Machine Co., 1942 (Box 2)
    - Budd Wheel Company, 1927-1929 (Box 2)
      (4 non-consecutive volumes)
    - Edward G. Budd Manufacturing Company credit and cash book, 1912-1913 (Volume 1)
    - Edward G. Budd Manufacturing Company Detroit factory credit and cash book, 1913-1914 (Volume 1)
    - Edward G. Budd Manufacturing Company journal C, 1920-1923 (Volume 1)